{
    "subject": "resource/Kilroy_was_here",
    "predicate": "ontology/abstract",
    "object": "Kilroy was here is an American popular culture expression that became popular during World War II; it is typically seen in graffiti. Its origins are debated, but the phrase and the distinctive accompanying doodle \u2014 a bald-headed man (sometimes depicted as having a few hairs) with a prominent nose peeking over a wall with the fingers of each hand clutching the wall \u2014 became associated with GIs in the 1940s.In the United Kingdom, the graffiti is known as \"Mr Chad\" or just \"Chad\", and the Australian equivalent to the phrase is \"Foo was here\". \"Foo was here\" might date from World War I, and the character of Chad may have derived from a British cartoonist in 1938, possibly pre-dating \"Kilroy was here\".  Etymologist Dave Wilton says, \"Some time during the war, Chad and Kilroy met, and in the spirit of Allied unity merged, with the British drawing appearing over the American phrase.\" \"Foo was here\" became popular amongst Australian schoolchildren of post-war generations. Other names for the character include Smoe, Clem, Flywheel, Private Snoops, Overby, The Jeep (as both characters had sizable noses), and Sapo.Author Charles Panati says that in the United States \"the mischievous face and the phrase became a national joke... The outrageousness of the graffiti was not so much what it said, but where it turned up.\" The major Kilroy graffiti fad ended in the 1950s, but today people all over the world still scribble the character and \"Kilroy was here\" in schools, trains, and other public areas.It is believed that James J. Kilroy was the origin of the expression, as he used the phrase when checking ships at the Fore River Shipyard.",
    "human_readable": "Kilroy was here is an American popular culture expression that became popular during World War II, typically seen in graffiti, and its origins are debated.",
    "questions": [
        {
            "score": 0.9036011099815369,
            "question": "During which historical conflict did 'Kilroy was here' become popular?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.848499059677124,
            "question": "What does the enduring popularity of 'Kilroy was here' tell us about its cultural significance?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.8228111267089844,
            "question": "How did people use 'Kilroy was here' during World War II?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.7993379831314087,
            "question": "What is the meaning of the expression 'Kilroy was here'?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.7843224406242371,
            "question": "Why do you think 'Kilroy was here' became so popular during wartime?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.7675876021385193,
            "question": "What form of expression is 'Kilroy was here' considered to be?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.7448976635932922,
            "question": "Where was 'Kilroy was here' typically found?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.727994441986084,
            "question": "Can you give some examples of other popular phrases or expressions that emerged during World War II?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.6078501343727112,
            "question": "Is the origin of 'Kilroy was here' definitively known?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.578982949256897,
            "question": "What does the expression 'Kilroy was here' suggest about the author?"
        }
    ],
    "google_pages": [
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=Kilroy was here is an American popular culture expression that became popular during World War II, typically seen in graffiti, and its origins are debated.",
            "html": "dbpedia_3912_0.html"
        },
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=Is the origin of 'Kilroy was here' definitively known?",
            "html": "dbpedia_3912_1.html"
        },
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=Can you give some examples of other popular phrases or expressions that emerged during World War II?",
            "html": "dbpedia_3912_2.html"
        },
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=Where was 'Kilroy was here' typically found?",
            "html": "dbpedia_3912_3.html"
        }
    ],
    "selected_docs": [
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_121.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_133.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_160.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_2.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_22.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_32.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_34.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_80.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_84.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_3912_85.txt"
        }
    ],
    "final_question": "Is true?",
    "responses": {
        "gemma2": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": "```json\n{'output': 'yes'}\n```"
        },
        "llama3.1": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": "```json\n{\n  \"output\": \"yes\"\n}\n```"
        },
        "qwen2.5": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": "```json\n{\n  \"output\": \"yes\"\n}\n```\n\nThe provided documents support the statement that \"Kilroy was here\" is an American popular culture expression that became popular during World War II and is typically seen in graffiti. The origins of the phrase are also noted to be debated, which aligns with the query."
        },
        "mistral": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": " {\"output\": \"yes\"}"
        }
    },
    "need_tiebreaker": false,
    "tiebreakers_responses": {
        "qwen2.5:14b": {},
        "llama3.1:70b": {}
    },
    "final_decision": 1,
    "actual_decision": 1,
    "analysis": {
        "stratum": "Less Popular",
        "topic": "-"
    },
    "errors": {}
}